{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which access control model allows for defining granular rules that consider user roles, time constraints, and network access restrictions?",
      "options": ["ABAC", "MAC", "RuBAC", "DAC", "RBAC"],
      "correct_answers": ["ABAC"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Examples of properties used for defining access policies in Attribute-Based Access Control (ABAC) model include:",
      "options": [
        "Subject (i.e., user or process requesting access)",
        "Type of action (for example \"read\", \"write\", \"execute\")",
        "Resource type (medical record, bank account etc.)",
        "Environment (contextual data, such as time of day or geolocation)",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["All of the above"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which access control model defines access control rules with the use of statements that closely resemble natural language?",
      "options": ["DAC", "ABAC", "MAC", "RBAC"],
      "correct_answers": ["ABAC"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the access control models listed below enforces the strictest set of access rules?",
      "options": ["MAC", "RBAC", "DAC", "ABAC"],
      "correct_answers": ["MAC"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following access control methods would be the most suitable for scheduling system maintenance tasks during periods of low user activity?",
      "options": ["Resource provisioning", "Time-of-day restrictions", "Principle of least privilege", "Just-in-time permissions"],
      "correct_answers": ["Time-of-day restrictions"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The principle of least privilege is a security rule that prevents users from accessing information and resources that lie beyond the scope of their responsibilities.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of IT security, the term \"Biometrics\" refers to both biological characteristics of the human body and behavioral traits that can be used for identification and access control purposes.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A measure of the likelihood that a biometric security system will incorrectly reject an access attempt by an authorized user is called:",
      "options": ["FAR", "CER", "CRC", "FRR"],
      "correct_answers": ["FRR"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refer(s) to a medium type that can be used as a hardware authentication token? (Select all that apply)",
      "options": ["Smart card", "Key fob", "Security key", "Passphrase", "Biometric reader", "RFID badge"],
      "correct_answers": ["Smart card", "Key fob", "Security key", "RFID badge"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following examples does not fall into the category of software authentication tokens?",
      "options": ["QR code token", "Security key", "SMS-based OTP", "Authenticator app", "Email-based OTP"],
      "correct_answers": ["Security key"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refer to the features of a security key? (Select 3 answers)",
      "options": [
        "Used for OTP generation, remote vehicle access, and building access",
        "Hardware authentication token",
        "Typically, a physical USB stick or key fob-sized device",
        "Primarily used for digital security (2FA/MFA)",
        "Software authentication token",
        "Typically, a credit card-sized plastic card with an embedded chip"
      ],
      "correct_answers": [
        "Hardware authentication token",
        "Typically, a physical USB stick or key fob-sized device",
        "Primarily used for digital security (2FA/MFA)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Authentication process can be based on various categories of authentication factors... A multifactor authentication system requires the implementation of authentication factors from two or more distinct categories.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["True"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The two factors that are considered important for creating strong passwords are: (Select 2 answers)",
      "options": ["Password length", "Minimum password age", "Password history", "Password complexity", "Maximum password age"],
      "correct_answers": ["Password length", "Password complexity"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A strong password that meets the password complexity requirement should contain: (Select the best answer)",
      "options": [
        "Uppercase letters (A-Z)",
        "Digits (0-9)",
        "Non-alphanumeric characters if permitted (e.g., !, @, #, $)",
        "Lowercase letters (a-z)",
        "A combination of characters from at least 3 character groups"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["A combination of characters from at least 3 character groups"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following passwords is the most complex?",
      "options": ["T$7C52WL4SU", "GdL3tU8wxYz", "@TxBL$nW@Xt", "G$L3tU8wY@z"],
      "correct_answers": ["G$L3tU8wY@z"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which password policy would be the most effective in decreasing the risk of a security breach across multiple accounts?",
      "options": ["Password expiration policy", "Minimum password age policy", "Password reuse policy", "Maximum password age policy"],
      "correct_answers": ["Password reuse policy"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which password policy enforces a mandatory password change after a specific time?",
      "options": ["Password expiration policy", "Password history policy", "Minimum password age policy", "Password reuse policy"],
      "correct_answers": ["Password expiration policy"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The minimum password age policy setting determines the period of time that a password can be used before the system requires the user to change it.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["False"]
    },
    {
      "question": "The maximum password age policy setting determines the period of time that a password must be used before the user can change it.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "correct_answers": ["False"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a software tool specifically designed to store and manage login credentials?",
      "options": ["BitLocker", "Password manager", "Key escrow", "Password vault"],
      "correct_answers": ["Password manager"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following technologies cannot be used as a passwordless authentication method?",
      "options": [
        "Biometrics",
        "Hardware tokens",
        "QR codes",
        "OTPs",
        "Passkeys",
        "All of the above can be used as a means for passwordless authentication"
      ],
      "correct_answers": ["All of the above can be used as a means for passwordless authentication"]
    },
    {
      "question": "A security solution that provides control over elevated (i.e., administrative type) accounts is referred to as:",
      "options": ["MFA", "IAM", "SSO", "PAM"],
      "correct_answers": ["PAM"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the answers listed below refers to a solution designed to minimize the risk of unauthorized access to privileged accounts?",
      "options": ["Principle of least privilege", "Just-in-time permissions", "Passwordless authentication", "Multifactor authentication"],
      "correct_answers": ["Just-in-time permissions"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following answers refers to an encrypted database that provides secure storage space for user credentials?",
      "options": ["Secure enclave", "Password manager", "Rainbow table", "Password vault"],
      "correct_answers": ["Password vault"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the terms listed below refer(s) to the concept of ephemeral access, where access to systems, resources, or permissions is provided for a limited duration? (Select all that apply)",
      "options": ["TOTP", "OTP", "Just-in-time permissions", "User password", "API key"],
      "correct_answers": ["TOTP", "OTP", "Just-in-time permissions"]
    }
  ]
}